With Allen, just the cerebral nature to
him, what did you notice from like a
green dot standpoint and trying to kind
of project him mentally into potentially
doing that for a living?
>> Yeah, high-level communicator. You see
that in person at practice, you see that
at the games, you see that on film. Um,
but yeah, highly instinctive. I think
he's got rare instincts for a college
football player. Um, so the reactive
quickness kind of allows him to play
faster.
And he's already fast, you know, he ran
ran really well a couple weeks ago.
But yeah, I just see a rare feel.
Um, and for a 2 and 1/2 year starter in
a complex system at Georgia,
there's a lot on his plate mentally. So,
definitely I could see green dot
potential for us. And he's handled that
the last 2 years at Georgia. How did you
see him grow at Georgia because I mean
to start the true freshman in any
capacity at a school like that probably
speaks to how smart he is. Yeah, um, I
just think that is a tough place to play
and practice and
man, he graduated from that program, I
like to say. So, it's a hard thing to
do. Um, but yeah, I mean to come in
there as a freshman amongst all those
really top talent in the country and
play early,
I just think that speaks to his prep out
of high school and his determination
just like his mental makeup and
maturity, man. Like he's just prepared,
he's diligent, he's detailed. Uh, he is
the best practice player I viewed this
fall, I thought, out of, you know, a few
hundred players. Um, just the intensity
and focus he had really stood out to me.
Gumbs is obviously a kind of a still, I
don't know, somewhat green in his
position transitioning from some
different spots on the roster over the
years
in his time at at Florida. What what do
you make of what his potential is and
maybe what's still kind of unscratched?
Yeah, I think there's a few things he
could clean up just technique-wise, like
skillset, hand usage, foot usage, having
a plan as a rusher. He's only been
rushing for 3 years. He was a walk-on
receiver at Northern Illinois.
Played some receiver, played some tight
end.
Uh, and then they they put him on
scholarship, then he played D end for 1
year and that's kind of how Florida
found him. Um, but yeah, he's a little
green. I I wouldn't say he's like super
raw though. Like there's enough there
where there's a good baseline of stuff
for us to work with as far as his
skillset.
Um, but man, you're seeing a guy like he
battled through some injuries this year.
So, the tape was like solid, it was
good, it was a little up and down
sometimes just cuz he was battling. Uh,
but man, you went to pro day, it was
excellent performance. I thought
movement athletically uh, really
impressed me in person.
And
obviously blew out the combine too with
his numbers, but you can you see that on
film too. How much when when a guy has
the tools like that, how much can that
it doesn't supersede the other stuff,
like technique issues or whatever, but
like how much can it make up for the
lack in other areas? Yeah, I think
you're just betting that, hey, this guy
can figure it out. And part of it is
like,
okay, he's got the talent, he's got
size, and then it's like, does he have
the football smarts and the the drive to
get better? Cuz you can have potential,
but like if you're not going to work at
it, it doesn't matter. And this is this
guy's wired the right way. Like super
into football, man, like I just think
it's a great story, man. This guy, you
know, like this guy pursued football. He
walked on at a play at a max school and
leveled up and started at a SEC school
and now is drafted to the NFL. So, he's
got some stuff to him where he's like
really determined, man. Um,
I I'm really high on the person. And I
think he's very talented as well. Mike,
with Halsey going from a couple of
programs and ending at LSU, what's that
tell you about his journey and
him earning all-conference honors and
everything else? For sure. I mean, it's
going to sound kind of similar to that
C.J. Allen's level of competitiveness.
You know, this kid, his drive,
just his innate
want to to compete at a higher level,
you know, and just continue to do that
and produce and perform and you know,
everywhere he goes, bet on himself and
earn a starting job and obviously, you
know, can pick up some accolades along
the way. You know, very similar to, you
know, the guy Anthony just talked about.
Skillset-wise, what stands out to you
about his game? So, he's strong, right?
He's got a compact muscular build, but I
wouldn't say, you know, don't let that
fool you because he's got a natural feel
for coverage too and he's quick. He can
change direction. Ran very well at the
combine, you know, so we feel good about
his long speed and range in the passing
game. Um, and again, I mean, he's not
scared to get his nose dirty in the run
game and he's got ball production on
paper, you know, that tells you he can
take it away.
Were you guys surprised he was still
there cuz he seems like physically and
athletically he seems like kind of one
of these modern safeties that never has
to leave the field. Like was it
surprising he would still be there? I
think I think, you know,
depending on who you ask, you know, some
people definitely thought he'd go a
little bit earlier, but we felt really
good about, you know, him being there
for us and and it was a no-brainer. What
do you think his experience helped him
with? He he talked about, hey, I played
in a bunch of different, you know,
systems along the way and
played, I think, over 700 snaps last
year. So,
Yeah, a lot of snaps, a lot of exposure
to different schemes, different
terminology.
That speaks to his football IQ. His
ability to kind of get to a new
environment, a new school, new program
and and pick it up like that, you know,
and not, hey, you're going to be the
backup until you learn it. Hit the
ground running and knew what he was
doing. So, feel confident about his
ability to do that here with us. Chris
was talking about this draft class as a
whole having some competitive stamina to
it. With Allen and Halsey maybe
specifically to start off, like how do
those guys fit that that sort of
description?
That's a shoe-in. I mean, I I think, you
know, as as you guys speak to other
people who scouted everybody on this
list, the consistent theme is going to
be their their competitiveness, their
edge, the grit that they play with.
That we were talking about earlier, we
know for a fact we got tougher with this
year's draft.
Mike, Burks lasted as long as he did.
It seemed like pretty much everywhere
you looked, they had him going much,
much earlier than seven. Were you pretty
surprised he was still there? Uh, yeah,
you know, we were. We tried to figure it
out amongst ourselves, you know, maybe
why, but, you know, either way, as as
that, you know, we kept looking up at
that card, you know, we felt good that
uh, we were getting really good value
for where we took him in the draft.
Smaller fast guys like that kind of just
get thrown into the they're a slot or
they're a vertical guy.
What about him makes you think he could
maybe be more of a consistent, maybe
like an every down
type of contributor [clears throat] and
not just a niche player? Sure, yeah. Not
not like your typical size that you want
out there, but I think this kid pound
for pound, his play strength and just
how well put together he is, I think he,
you know, should not be exclusively
labeled a slot receiver. You know, I
think he has the speed to kind of
threaten vertically no matter where you
line him up on the field. And then, you
know, in some situations again, that
that play strength, you know, catches
through contact or he's outside the
numbers, I think, you know, he can do
more than than just play inside in my
opinion.
Was that 26 bench reps, was that legit
at the combine? Very legit.
Very legit, yeah.
He [laughter] is, yeah, he's, like I
said, you know,
at his size, pound for pound, I mean,
this kid is very, very strong, very
explosive. You can feel it when he's
coming off the ball.
And and again, you can feel it when he's
running through contact. I think that
bench press is consistent with what we
kind of saw on film. How many of these
guys how many of these guys hit the
portal at some point in their college
career? Like
how does that impact the scouting
process? Is it beneficial or are there
challenges that come with it? Both you
guys.
Yeah, there's definitely [clears throat]
some challenges. Um,
I think, you know, like last year, I
think we hit on Travis cuz he kind of
transferred up from Princeton. Uh, Gumbs
transferred up, you would say,
to Halsey, you know, going to LSU.
Um, so I think that speaks to them. But
yeah,
for our scouting process, there's
there's a little more hurdles when they
bounce around just because if you're at
a place for 1 year, how well do they
really know you? Um, and I know for a
fact like all these guys, we've vetted
them at their their current school and
their previous school. Current position
coach, previous position coach.
Coordinator, coordinator. So, we do our
due diligence at both schools. So, it
takes a little longer to get all the
information, but we follow the same
process and steps. But that is uniquely
changed the past couple years with the
portal is like you're making a lot more
calls.
Uh, they may be a little shorter, but
you're calling more people to get A to Z
on them.
For [clears throat] for Burks, um,
return-wise, do you think he can offer
something there? Yeah, I mean, he's done
it at Purdue. He's been a kick returner
there.
No live game reps as a punt returner,
but I think the the toughness, the
ability to track it and field it, you
know, definitely things that he has in
his toolbox that suggests he'll be able
to do that for us. You know, might take
some take him a little bit of time to
figure it out cuz he hasn't done it live
yet, but
has done kicks. And again, I think he's
got the toughness, the speed, the
instincts, the vision. I think he'll
he'll be a guy that
should be able to develop in that
department for us.